Mark Morrison's Return of the Mac has
spawned many redos that's another Ace
One the Mac by man my guest of the day
is on the show
now this is good morning Mumbai with
Rishi
K speaking to one of my favorite people
in lockdown really got to stay positive
and what better than to have this friend
of mine and a captain of the industry on
the show sanjie manri executive director
at ICC Lombard good to see you how are
you holding up in these trying times
always a pleasure meeting you is and
your voice makes me more positive truly
but it's been one of those difficult
time that we have lived through in last
3 months completely never thought of
none of the BCPS none of none of us ever
thought that we have to exist in a
manner the way we are existing as a you
know as a country as a individuals as
families in this particular manner so
strange time but human race is always
full of optimism as you said so a lot
more to look forward to rather than what
has gone last in the last few months
also professionally you've been keeping
very very busy IC lombar has been coming
up with lots of initiatives during the
covid-19 lockdown we've seen special
products being launched sanjie lots of
Digital Services being offered what is
the thought process that you've adopted
in the new normal as a company so
clearly you know R from our thought
process you know what we stand for the
philosophy which you have been talking
about we clearly want to stand with the
customers and in this hour of need and
in today's scenario if you look at it
we've gone through a complete
transformation of the way you know we
were existing so and some of the things
that we indulge in and one of them being
health you know health insurance is a
very key requirement we felt it is
important that we change the way we are
operating if you ask me as a company
again we've been at the Forefront of
putting in digitization but lot of it
that we putting as convenience the
adoption used to be always a challenge
you know the current scenario that is
prevailing it has gone through a
multiple level of adoption which
otherwise wasn't existing so lot what
we've been doing for you know years
together we've been in this business
over last two decades has culminated and
we've seen people really accepting and
adopting it to just give you an example
to make my point you know I take care
one of the apps that we had on the
health insurance side we have ensured
that today each one of our customer
through this particular thing can aail
of two tel consultation and you will
understand that in today's situation
people are not very comfortable visiting
doctors visiting hospitals but they
require professional advice from the
doctor to take care it's not that other
ailments have gone away they are still
there you can get a normal fever you can
have some other stomach upset all of it
pretty much exists in today's scenario
also so through this particular aspect
they can reach out to professionals who
will not only give you the right advice
but also give you an e prescription and
after that you can even order those
medicines online and get the same
delivered so it's an end to end
solutioning which has been done taking
into care what the current situation is
and we have seen tremendous response
with lot more of our customers reaching
out b as what the volumes used to be so
our whole belief is we need to stand by
in this hour of need and do whatever is
appropriate for our customers that's
very sensitive indeed more up ahead on
the show with sanjie montry executive
director ICI Lomar General Insurance
company I'm Keen to know if there are
more inquiries from consumers during
this covid crisis let's break for some
call playay and adventure of a lifetime
I'm Rishi K and you're tuned in to 94.3
radio11 World y Station Post Malone what
a special talent he is that's better now
sanjie monry executive director ICI
lombar General Insurance company is my
guest of the day more
conversation this is good morning Mumbai
with re
K so let's spend a little more time
about your customers the response you're
getting on your products there's
obviously a lot of heightened awareness
around health because of the pandemics
and even that's a good thing are you
seeing more inquiries from consumers on
health insurance as a category yeah you
I think a very very valid question again
I'll give you some examples this social
you know media conversation on health
typically used to average around a
million in current times they've gone to
5 million on health insurance we have
seen inquiries moving to the tune of 3
and a half time 350% to 400% and it's
quite clear you know a lot of protection
people seek when there is fear you
that's why the big change of psychology
which I can say in the mindset of
individuals if you ask me every time
I've come even on your show Rishi I've
been always saying that to sell health
insurance is actually a service you are
helping a particular family to make sure
that in case of an excy they're able to
protect themselves through health
insurance in India nothing less than 25
to 30 million families go below poverty
line because they don't have a health
insurance cover so clearly this was the
need of the art but what the current
scenario has done and which is a big
positive is if you have to look for a
positive of course the times are
challenging because of this pandemic is
the fact that people have started
looking at Health cover or health
protection as more of an investment
rather than expense and to me this is a
very very significant change in the
minds of the customer I want to commend
you and ICI lomard for the home health
care benefit in your health insurance
policies I mean I really think it's
pioneering and the need of the hour I
mean for those of you who are watching
or listening to this broadcast it means
you can now get your health insurance
with you to pay for treatment even if
you don't get admitted to a hospital and
I think that makes a lot of sense in the
current times when there's social
distancing what made you come up with
that particular facility who do you
think will this benefit be most relevant
for pleas so I will probably break this
into two parts in terms of the benefit
product that you're talking about rash
is typically the one which we launch in
the early stage somewhere in you know
April itself where we realize that the
pandemic is spreading his tentacles in
the country and we need to be cautious
while there was no explicit Trends
available but we took a leap of faith
more with the intent of servicing the
customer may we said that if you get
impacted by covid and you know for a
fact that 880 85% people technically
don't even require hospitalization
because they can cure themselves through
self isolation at home so with that
particular aspect we said that on a
price of 150 rupees you will be able to
get a benefit cover of 25,000 which we
had accessed through our very eminent
Channel partners by which we were
dispensing this particular product so
that was one part of the solutioning
that was done at very early stages now
the other one which you're talking about
in terms of extending the benefit of the
cover to our other set of customers is
the home care benefit you're talking
about we realized that in today's
scenario customers are very wary of
visiting the doctors or the hospitals
for other ailm so there is a clear fear
cyclosis that has existing because you
may get impacted whenever you're meeting
or getting into a place where there have
people who you don't know are coming in
I mean even known people you are very
very of interacting you're avoiding
abing it so in this situation we have
given a customer the benefit of having
Home Care in this particular aspect if
you require this through Professional
Network partner that we have on hand we
will give you the access to the hospital
if you need nurse in your house you will
get a nurse in your house medicines if
there are some basic equipment that are
required the cost of those equipments so
host of activity that is required which
can be made available to you which can
help you in getting fit and proper again
those EXP will will B will be B by us as
I say Lombard and you can get yourself
cure the whole idea is that if you defer
your treatment you may convert this into
a much more critical illness which make
things much more difficult for you and
everyone you must do it and purely
taking that into account we have given
this particular option to our customers
which is through home care benefit Big
Ups to you and ICI Lombard for this
sanjie manri executive director shall
return up ahead my name is Rishi K and
I'm in a detailed discussion with him
slipping in Hall and marshmallows hit
now this one's called be kind only on
94.3 Radio One One World your station
Stronger by Kelly Clarks and sanjie
monry from ICC lomard is on the show he
was just telling me about a home
healthcare benefit in their insurance
policies more on that with the executive
director this is good morning Mumbai
with reishi
K I'm just going to add on to the
modalities and the logistics of it
you've always tried to keep the
operational aspect very very simple for
anybody who's using your product uh how
does it literally work in what cases can
one get one's health insurance to pay
for treatment at home does there have to
be a recommendation yes of course I mean
there has to be a process which will
come into place suppose if you visit to
any of the hospital which happens to be
a network partner through that and the
and the hospital the doctors or the
experts in this are comfortable in
giving you home treatment then they will
apply to us through our Healthcare and
you know that I Lomar does not operate
to CPO we have our own Healthcare
assistance facility which will evaluate
approval as we do it quite quickly and
from there on you can move to your
residence and all the expenses that are
to be B with respect to that will be
taken care of by ICS but suppose another
in instance where you end up visiting a
hospital which is not part of a network
coverage the network part of coverage
that I'm talking about in that scenario
once you reach out to a call center for
the approval and we believe that this is
the best solution any which way for you
which would be given by the expert then
you can take the reimbursement through
our claim another option which is
available alternatively is in the event
of you not feeling comfortable again you
can reach to our health care center and
from there we can advise you which way
you can be helped and taken care of by
being provided a Solutions at home so
there are multiple options that have
been made available by which as a
customer of I you will get this option
fantastic so you're basically saying
that if you have your own home care
doctor or hospital that is not on the
impaneled list you're still going to go
ahead with it as long as they take prior
authorization absolutely absolutely you
can you can come just to clarify again
to my listeners you can reach out
through the hospital where we'll approve
it if you want to reach out to us
directly we'll help you with respect to
where you can go and get this facility
one way or the other the needs of the
customer will be taken care of with the
pressure on the Indian economy uh sanjie
I think a lot of people are trying to
remain a float and financially stable
and secure uh you've also introduced a
feature wherein even if one is covid-19
positive one tests positive the
cumulative bonus accumulated does not
get deducted tell our listeners about
this particular unique feature please
yeah I think this another peace to take
care of current times in terms of what's
happening on the pandemic we do expect
that there are quite a few cases which
are building up as a country we can see
the challenge we're talking of almost
three and a half lakh cases which are
already up there which have got impacted
by covid it's also possible that our
customers will get impacted just to make
this point clear conventionally if you
have taken health insurance Rishi and
you have not claimed anything your some
insured next year gives through an
enhancement you get a typically in most
cases it increases by 10% without an
extra cost however in the year where you
make a claim because of your
hospitalization this particular benefit
is not given what as a company we have
taken a call is if you make any claims
on account of covid related expenses we
will exempt you and your no claim bonus
your cumulative some insure that is due
to you will be made available to you
next year so there will be no impact for
you and your family because of covid
claim we believe that the customer
deserve this typically a pandemic of
this magnitude is something which you
and me can't be part of and people are
getting impacted in spite of taking all
the precautions it's a challenging
situation and it would not be fair to
impact the Journey of a customer which
otherwise has been absolutely superb in
terms of its own Fitness his own Fitness
his or her own Fitness really focusing
on the well-being of the consumer and
putting that before profit in these
trying times executive director ICI
Lombard General Insurance company sanjie
mtri showing the way this interview
shall continue with me rishy K so don't
go anywhere let's do some Bond joy and
have a nice day only on 94.3 radio one
one world station Calvin Aris and
Rihanna are firing up the hits with this
is what you came for it's one of those
business interviews which puts the focus
on Healthcare even above Revenue sanjie
monre executive director of ICI lombar
General Insurance company on a slew of
people-friendly measures introduced by
them to combat
Co this is good morning Mumbai with
Rishi
K sanjie the cooling or the waiting
period of 30 days is again a cause of
worry I mean in times like this paranoia
sets in because of various reasons what
about new customers have you introduced
any covid-19 specific facilities for
them elaborate on that please yeah no no
so absolutely this was another thing
clearly we felt that if you buy a new
policy and this again is the industry
Norm for first 30 days you're not
allowed to make certain claims because
of the fear that you would have got
impacted and P that you would have
purchased your policy but a 30-day
period today's scenario on covid is not
a workable man naturally we have seen
that people are buying insurance with
intent of getting themselves protected
so on an exceptional I think it's a
first of his kind from a 30-day cooling
period for covid related cases you can
actually claim after 15 days so you've
bought a policy on day one after 15 days
on 16 17 18 day if you're positive on
account of covid in the unfor it's
unfortunate I hope and pray that no one
ever gets impacted but just in case it
happens and there related expenses for
this it can be taken care of also
another thing you know I was saying 80
85% of the cases you don't need to get
hospitalized you can manage yourself by
getting yourself quarantined at your
home if there are covid expense also
that comes in because you have been
yourself into isolation at your own
residence and the related expenses on
that that also will be taken care of so
this is purely with the intent of
addressing the need of the r for our
customers across the country excellent
so you know the extraordinary times call
for Extraordinary Measures and all of us
are having to look inward during this
phase of lockdown for example I I gave
you my own example that you know I've
tried to learn some audio software
trying to balance the levels in my home
studio and this and that and all of us
who are positive people fundamentally do
that you know we try not to look behind
get pulled down by life in its
circumstances so any new skill that
you've picked up during this lockdown
anything that you can look back and say
I did new or special during the covid-19
crisis well I think in terms of the new
skills I quite clearly received work
from home for not days weeks and now
it's months itself has been learning I'm
I'm quite thankful because now my kids
actually believe that their papa does
have some work otherwise there was a
clear belief that by the time he comes
back in the night he's a free man and
they've seen me just ging around or
fooling around also you have probably
started doing an odd jobs here and there
which otherwise were not required
because you were missing a fair amount
of interesting time with the kids
honestly there is lot more learning in
terms of how they've been going about
most of it in a way you know we would
have realized in our working life and
I'm sure the same for you you've got a
young one at your house as of now just
10 months old right so there is
there is so much joy you know in
spending time with them but I must also
add this as I say I want to get back to
work as soon as possible and and how's
the fitness going I mean with limited
measures are you using the apartment
complex the home to get your Fitness
going uh I must say that when the
lockdown came in the last week of March
there was a bit of w set in and for
almost a week I was just wondering if
because I've been a more an outdoors guy
playing long tennis short running and
with that being compromised in the
current situ situation I had no idea
which way to do it but eventually I did
get it right and probably from first
week of April virtually every day some
you know process I follow in terms of
keeping myself fit I realized stairs is
a very handy option available I mean I
live in a highrise building and there
were there's a decent workout that you
can do it became part of my routine been
doing a little bit of weight so there's
something or the other but I would
Clearly say that I have been Physically
Active but for to days where I can get
back to Road and do my normal runs and
live that normally because there's
pleasure in running and being closer to
Nature or whatever you can get in Mumbai
I know that once a runner always a
runner and I see some Runners are
getting back you know Milan Sans is back
on the road rul BOS is back on the road
how do you view getting out and just
going for a run in lockdown or semi
lockdown so interestingly you know there
was a study that got done recently and
they were try to put across the risk in
each of these Sports the risk level one
and two which is probably you know in
the order of being the lowest starting
from risk 10 which is the highest they
put across running as number two which
is something which I indulge in and they
put one tenis actually you should be
happy to know I was put as one mean the
lowest risk sport that you can indulge
in current situations so I have started
going out I wouldn't say it's a regular
thing but I did spend weekend running at
PDP and on Mar Drive the comfort is
there and yes the fellow Runners who are
there each one of them knows what's
expected of them in terms of social
distancing and you know all the Norms
that are required to make sure that we
not creating anything which is
challenging for each other so that disp
is anywhere in are supposed to be
relatively a disciplined lot so we
following what is required I do believe
that I would start and get back two
three times a week being on the road
eventually now with all these Norms
which are advised will be followed to
the deed no exception to that for sure
easier to motivate your employees when
you yourself are setting the right
Fitness and Wellness examples the
inspirational sanjie monry there a last
leg of conversation with the executive
director of IC Loma that's still to come
as I play you some common and
brokenhearted I'm Rishi K and you're
tuned in to 94.3 radio 111 World your
station Luis fony and steflon Don acing
the Latin Pop that's the worldwide gem
Calypso eventful Monday morning
interview with the dynamic sanjie monry
executive director IC lombar General
Insurance Company Limited a last
leg this is good morning Mumbai with REI
K let's sign off with your your parting
thoughts on everybody who's listening uh
to this broadcast these are trying times
testing times what is your message to
consumers customers this is the Great
Indian story and you know Big Ups to you
and IC Lombard for keeping the medical
insurance flag flying high and really
going out of your way to pull out all
stops uh to increase safety for for the
common man what are your parting
thoughts so Rishi I think I I'm an
eternal optimist in terms of knowing
that and you and you know it for a fact
that I would believe things will get
normalized lot of people say that this
is technically The New Normal this is
the way we lead our life I think human
race place is not designed to live in
this particular manner uh you know in
for periods together we would find a
solution things will get back to normal
but till that time I think prevention is
better than cure so you must do what is
required to abstain in the event if you
getting it you know the CH the fact is
it can happen to anybody I think there's
no social stigma involved it is part of
the process fortunately this disease has
not differentiated between classes and
masses it's coming to each one of us in
particular manner stay optimistic stay
good I think Fitness will play a big
role we need to make sure that we invest
in ourselves to keep ourselves you know
in the right frame of mind and those end
offs that come with the workout can go a
long way and in putting us in positive
manner you need to be certain that you
are you know taking care of your near
and dear was to the best of your ability
India story stays intact nothing has
changed there's a minor blip but we'll
be back and we already seen that may was
better than April June is better than
May so progressively Rishi things will
keep improving and we'll have we'll have
good times rolling again sanjie before
we sign off uh I've got to ask you uh
because of the times that we live in has
it perhaps affected claim settlements
because when you when you take an
insurance policy one of the things you
that are foremost in your mind and which
concern you most is the speed of claim
settlement and the percentage of claim
settlements it's a very valid question
because the lockdown was sudden and it
did derail the call center it did impact
the ability of a customers to reach out
out to us but I'm very happy to state to
you that our metrices in terms of
delivering what was required to the
customer have got completely untouched
so we've stuck to what we have been as a
company and there are few reasons for
that if you remember you know some time
back maybe a year back or maybe almost
18 months back I had come to the show
and said that we have started using AI
you know artificial intelligence in
terms of approving the claims and almost
onethird of our claims today get
approved within seconds of they reaching
to us so all the technological
interventions that we had done she has
gone a long way in be delivering to our
customers where they are not able to
reach out to some other in a in a you
know in a normal process which they use
to so we've remained unaffected and I
can assure all the customers that I see
s Lombard that this will remain a
promise which you want to stand by come
me under the same thing which we said
beautiful I'll tell you one thing that I
did miss this time around is that
normally I meet you in my studio or
elsewhere and you give me a firm
handshake and sometimes a hug and
virtual handshakes and virtual hugs are
Never As Good so I look forward to
meeting you soon in person take care of
yourself sanjie manri thank you so much
isik it's been a pleasure and look
forward to seeing you sooner than later
that was sanjie manry executive director
IC lomard my guest of the day on the
show here's the Bieber Grand Day song
stuck with you only on 94.3 radio11
World station my name is Rishi Kai